<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrick Johnson</title>
    <description>Patrick Johnson is a front-end developer working in New York City. He helps companies build websites and bakes delicious cookies.</description>
    <link>http://pbj.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://pbj.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:03:20 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 13:03:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who Cares?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does your app work with Vue.js even though all your friends are using React.js? If yes, then who cares.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you still get work without having a portfolio? If yes, then who cares?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you learn better from reading books instead of watching videos? If yes, then who cares?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you earn money by building sites with PHP instead of a Ruby (on Rails)? If yes, then who cares?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Did you just buy new running shoes right before the new All Birds released? If yes, who cares?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Did you learn JavaScript by way of  jQuery? If yes, who cares?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list could go on forever but you get the picture. The reality with our work, and our lives, is we all do things differently. Unless you’re doing something really wrong, who cares?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your intentions are well-formed and your work is well-crafted all that matters is helping someone, or something, progress forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not work at the hottest startup or on the newest product. If you enjoy your life, work and everything in between then who cares about what others are doing? You don’t need to follow the “herd” to be happy. You can achieve your personal, professional and financial (or any other) goals by following your intuition, gut and common sense. You can be you and still be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could spend our days arguing over skeuomorphic design vs flat and the “resurgence” of brutalist sites but will it make our lives, our customers’ lives, or families’ lives better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, you can have an opinion, you can voice it, you can scream it from the tallest rooftops but here’s the kicker, &lt;strong&gt;your opinion may not be someone’s fact&lt;/strong&gt;. It isn’t a truth to be told and held over the heads of others in or outside our industry. Your way of doing something may be right for you and your organization, but it may wrong for a friend or another company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our peers are a good barometer for quality but we still must trust our gut to find the right fit, tool, direction. And ultimately, who cares if the decision you make goes directly against the herd as long as you’re happy and it’s positive for you without negatively impacting others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue to be you, try new things and be open. If you pause because of what other’s may think just ask yourself one question - who cares?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://graybike.co/&quot;&gt;Pavan Trikutam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sandpiper.co/&quot;&gt;Monte Brown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sofetch.io/&quot;&gt;Corey Grusden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kylecrawford.co/&quot;&gt;Kyle Crawford&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing and editing this post before publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/who-cares.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/who-cares.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Year In Review - 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot happened for me in 2016 I thought it would be helpful to reflect and review it and consider improvements for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engaged-&quot;&gt;**Engaged! **&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of December 16, 2016 I’m engaged to a wonderful woman named Anna. I’ve managed to not piss her off too much during our five years together. A lot of our friends know how happy she was when we got engaged (like most folks) partly because I purposely dragged it out for over a year. Mostly cause I really wanted to think about the ring and the engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my birthday in 2015 I asked a friend, Mark, a question. It’s a question his grandmother asked him and it’s the only question to ask when contemplating marriage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you live your life without her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Mark was leaving the venue we were at, I knew I’d ask Anna to marry me. Fast forward 15 months and there we are, engaged!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the best night of my life and I can’t wait to get married, start a life together and one day start a family. Anna’s the best. And no, Anna did not make me write that last sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freelance-work&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freelance Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I wanted to see how much work I could do (not from a monetary aspect) to figure out my threshold. This year I challenged myself to see how much money I could make with higher quality projects. As a result, I almost doubled my freelancing income from last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;freelance-results&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Freelance Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Total Freelance revenue: $83,132.50&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Highest Paying Freelance Project: $20,000&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Longest Freelance Client: 2+ years (on going contract)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Freelance Hours Worked: &lt;strong&gt;467.81&lt;/strong&gt; Hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Weight Gained: 20 pounds (but stayed the same weight)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelance consumes most of my spare time. Although I think I’ve gotten better about managing workload and finding time to enjoy my life while still getting work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to get better about managing overlapping clients in a more consistent way. Overlapping projects are usually managed based on priority and deadline. This isn’t a sure-fire way to get work done but it helped manage my workload, planning projects and meeting deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, communication was a big area of improvement and I think 2016 saw even larger gains. Slack alone helped resolve a lot of thoughts around consistent communication, access to transparent conversations and a feeling of general connectivity to clients and projects. Whether it was jumping into a client’s group or inviting them into my own Slack allowed me to give a quick update, provide some long commentary to an issue or just pop in and say hello. I feel closer to clients without increasing email or guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fighting-burnout&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fighting Burnout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burnout is still a thing. It really hit towards the Holidays when a 2-week vacation was just around the corner. However, I felt less burnt out in 2016 than 2015 overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I believe it was mostly due to adjusting my perspective with projects. Rather than feeling like a project was this large daunting obligation I broke projects into smaller pieces. Setting up a client staging was a piece. Thinking through the front-end approach was another. As projects progressed, I was able to take small chunks out of large projects, which really helped out mentally. Especially if I was working for six hours on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-life&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never thought my personal life would change as much as it did over the last twelve months. My professional life was my top priority and I certainly paid my dues. Three big things happened this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Didn’t lose the weight I gained from last year&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Got engaged&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terrible with finances (IMO)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nutritionists are well worth their service. It’s a person whose specialization is in food. Not just the good and bad, but everything. It’s like a food version of a financial planner. And even some insurances cover it. So for me, it was $0 out of my pocket to see Ryan and help me understand what the best foods are for me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yay got engaged! Mentioned this above :)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 2016 I made ~$83,000. As of this writing, I have about ~40,000 in savings. This is all before taxes have been taken out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight-gain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Gain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I gained roughly 20lbs. I went from 180 to 200 in a couple of months. 2016 was my year to remove that weight, and maybe a little more. It didn’t happen. As I write this I’m hovering around my weight from December 2015 even though I started eating better, seeing a nutritionist and tried to make a habit of going to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t seen my nutritionist in 2017 yet but I’ve made a goal myself to lose 3 pounds a month. Considering this post is being published in March, I’m down from 200 pounds started to ~190 pounds. Ten pounds in two months feels great but I’m hoping to keep my loss consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly to me the loss so far as been from eating only when I’m hungry. I used to believe weight loss happened from sweating and working out but so far this year I’ve just chosen to only eat food when I’m hungry and that alone has helped me reduce weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing says motivation like fitting into a tuxedo to marry the great woman on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-overall&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health in 2016 was a roller coaster. While actively seeking to lose weight I ended up injuring my hamstring pretty severely. I’d say that was the point I lost momentum and fell back into the shitty-eating rabbithole. This year will be about taking care of my body as much as it is being active. Things like stretching, eating right, sleeping well (it’s 1AM as I write this, like an idiot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More on finances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year sucked in the money department due to a lack of responsibility and discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelance money acted as “start up” costs for Anna and I at times when we needed to finally get our own TV or a couch we enjoyed or that dining table we needed. It also acted as the debt-fund from times when I overspent on my credit card (like a dummy). I did pay quarterly taxes (although inconsistently) so I know where that went but the rest I’m sure went to ill-timed purchases, stupid stuff and eating out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 my goals are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not spend a dime of freelance money for anything but freelance expenses&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pay off all student loans* (doing this with freelance money will explain)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fund a wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelance money is meant for the freelance business. So this means the only money that gets spent from it is the money to run the business. Things like lawyer costs, subscriptions for products I use, etc. None of it will be used to supplement my cost of living in anyway until the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finally starting to realize how important it is to me to become financially independent. Not just the common, popular lifestyle definition of “financially independent” where people reach “FI” and retire at 40 but mostly just debt free and able to manage money responsibly. To not spend above my means and really master my credit cards to make the most out of my purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have about $30,000 in student loans currently and hoping to be able to pay that debt mostly down this year with the remaining freelance money (after taxes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal-projects&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to last year, personal projects were not a priority. While I did finish season four of &lt;a href=&quot;http://thestart.fm&quot;&gt;The Start&lt;/a&gt; I didn’t get much else done. I think my perspective last year was pretty shitty when it came to side projects. I either considered it more work or didn’t realize the monetary they could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working on Anna’s site at the end of last year I realized side projects can be pretty fun and fulfilling. Mostly because it’s something you &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to do, not because you want the money attached to it. Building Anna’s site was pure joy because I knew it’s something she’d love, share and use daily. It feels good to work on those kinds of projects so I hope to continue the trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on revamping &lt;a href=&quot;http://thestart.fm&quot;&gt;The Start&lt;/a&gt; this year as 2016 was a bummer when it came to publishing episodes. My process was inefficient and not very effective. With some research, I’ve planned ways to automate the publishing process so it’s less burdensome, published consistently and allows me to focus on the fun stuff - interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I hope to also do something fun with the show as well. I’ll keep you posted on that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-spent&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Spent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I tracked a lot of time, working or otherwise, and it’s been really helpful to determine if I spent time doing things I deem “of value”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn’t read that many books in 2016. I feel like a loser cause I personally love books and the availability of entertainment and knowledge you can get from them. Here are two books I really enjoyed last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shallows-What-Internet-Doing-Brains/dp/0393339750&quot;&gt;The Shallows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dog-Stars-Vintage-Contemporaries/dp/0307950476/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;Dog Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591846447/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Start With Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1936891379/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Do The Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1936891034/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Measure-What-Matters-Customers-Predictive/dp/0471752940&quot;&gt;Measure What Matters to Customers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;movies-watched&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movies Watched&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent roughly 70+ hours watching 36 movies. Movies acted as the medium for quality time with Anna, whether part of a date or just a chill night in. It was a way to unwind with the person I care about the most. A big change from last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On paper, this was a pretty great year. Mentally it’s a pretty good year, too. I feel like I’m finally settling into my career, learning about myself, my desires and my interest and finally understand how to really master a craft (hint: patience and persistence). I made some mistakes but we all do so I’ll try my best to make a mental note and keep moving. I’m really excited for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/year-in-review-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/year-in-review-2016.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working Together and Together Working</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2016/08/developers-own-code-should-designers-own-experience/&quot;&gt;read an article on Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, which, on first read, infuriated me as a developer. After reading a second time it was clear to see the author, a user-experience designer, was also frustrated but saw the light at the end of the tunnel. And the light, in this case, was teamwork. The topic in question: the working relationship between designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both sides of the table have different ideas on what should be standard and what the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; side should do and expect. Funny thing: both sides want the other side to do more than they are currently doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this happens, there is one idea to remind us of why this relationship between designers and developers is the most important piece of a successful work product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design without development is a picture and development without design is a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth discussing some of the points brought up in the Smashing Magazine article from a developer’s perspective. Not to bash the author’s intention or thoughts, but to bring light from the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-developers-claim-that-the-particular-target-experience-isnt-technically-possible-which-is-often-shorthand-for-really-difficult-i-cant-be-bothered-doing-it-that-way-or-i-think-theres-a-better-way-of-doing-it-so-am-going-to-pull-the-dev-card&quot;&gt;“… if [developers] claim that the particular target experience isn’t ‘technically possible’, which is often shorthand for ‘really difficult’, ‘I can’t be bothered doing it that way’ or ‘I think there’s a better way of doing it so am going to pull the dev card.’”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no dev-card. There is no “I can’t be bothered doing it that way” and there is no “I think there’s a better way of doing it so am going to pull the dev card”. There are, however, differing ideas or expectations. There are communication issues and misalignments. There are ideas lost due to lack of context, different priorities for different teams and a constantly changing project scope and feature sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we think of teams we usually think of the design team, product team, development team, sales team, etc. We don’t consider teams made up of multidisciplinary groups. Teams aren’t created the “MadMen” way - pairing an art director and copywriter together to create the work. And because our teams are grouped differently they have different goals, structure, and reasons for doing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few scenarios to illustrate this idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scenario-group&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;scenario-group__title&quot;&gt;Scenario One&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; A designer passes off design files to a developer for reference while building a responsive site. Once the developer is at a good stopping point she shares the work with the designer. The designer immediately notices a bunch of “bugs” with spacing and type.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; The design files were handed over in two formats: mobile and desktop. The mobile comps at 375px and desktop at 1200px. The design team chose 375px and 1200px based on client reviews and approvals. However, the developer must consider all devices and starts at 320px. Due to the 55px different the developer went ahead and adjusted some spacing and font-sizes to ensure it fit accordingly for the real-world user.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Prior to starting any work, the team comes together to determine deliverables. Deliverables can vary between projects but should include sizes of designed screens, breakpoints and what should happen in between them. The respective expertises come together to create the best experience for the client and project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scenario-group&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;scenario-group__title&quot;&gt;Scenario Two&lt;/h4&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; A designer walks a developer through a feature and all is going great. A few weeks later, due to adjusted business requirements, the design team is tasked with updating the original feature to accommodate a few more things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; The developer says “this changes a lot”. Their response to the update in this feature is such because the unforeseen implications the changes carry are larger than the team considered. Feature X wasn’t meant to hold a video in the background or Feature Y wasn’t intended to upload images. So the developer is required to rewrite the feature or write a new one from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Include frequent stand-up meeting to discuss status of the project. Set the standard to include all team appropriate team members when discussing changes and how they may impact the overall work product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scenario-group&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;scenario-group__title&quot;&gt;Scenario Three&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; As the project moves from the “design phase” to “dev phase” (typically happens in a waterfall environment versus an agile). The design team hands over some awesome prototypes through InVision and a few video files to help all parties understand the feeling and visualize the interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; While these assets are great for visual references, it does not help the developer recreate the animations and transitions in production code. There are no references to &lt;a href=&quot;http://cubic-bezier.com&quot;&gt;speed, timing, or easing&lt;/a&gt; and the developer must eyeball all of it in hopes they get it right. &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/communicating-animation&quot;&gt;Something that could’ve taken two hours with documentation ended up taking six&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
   

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Similar to Scenario one, the overall team sets standards on what is to be expected for the project. In the case of prototypes and animations, the team sets standards together on what should be expected in handoff. It could be video, story-boards or even comparable sites to review similar animations in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scenario-group&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;scenario-group__title&quot;&gt;Scenario Four&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; The design team sets up a hand-off meeting with the development team to review the latest round of designs for Product X before development starts. Through this meeting the design team reviews concepts and prototypes, and explains expected functionality and features. Some items are mandatory and some are nice-to-haves.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Perspective:&lt;/strong&gt; The features presented are met with questions and concerns by the development team. This review meeting is the first time they’ve seen these designs. They are worried the timeline isn’t adequate to build and some features aren’t even possible due to legacy code and infrastructure. But since it&#39;s already been “sold to the client” the development team is left find some way to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Set the standard up front to ensure appropriate (and necessary) team members have seen (and signed off) on the work being presented to the client for approval. This ensures appropriate (and necessary) team members are on board with the proposed work. It’s even more helpful to inform all team members who the designated team lead is ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scenario-disclaimer&quot;&gt;
  *These are just a few for scenarios from my work experience, colleagues and friends. 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes priorities are different between teams. Even more so, priorities, timelines and deadlines can shift, slide, change and get reworked all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The best thing we can do as teams is this: bring everyone together from day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Suggestions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage smaller huddles - informal, quick meetings, generally done when the development or design process is about to begin as a moment for everyone to ensure they are on the same page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include everyone in all meetings invites (setting appropriate folks as mandatory and others optional).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have weekly (or every couple days) check-ins with all parties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup project process, expectations, and internal deliverables up front before the project begins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;it-often-feels-as-though-theres-an-asymmetric-level-of-respect-between-disciplines-due-to-a-belief-that-design-is-easy-and-therefore-something-everybody-can-have-an-opinion-on-while-development-is-hard-and-only-for-the-specially-initiated&quot;&gt;“… it often feels as though there’s an asymmetric level of respect between disciplines due to a belief that design is easy and therefore something everybody can have an opinion on, while development is hard and only for the specially initiated.”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design isn’t easy. Development isn’t easy. If they were easy, both professions wouldn’t be highly sought after and yield six-figure salaries in some areas of the US. If design were easy, the US Government wouldn’t need to create the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usds.gov/&quot;&gt;US Digital Service&lt;/a&gt; to coordinate those exact efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design and development aren’t easy, but they become easier when we work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t the only ones in the world who have to work together. Consider other professions building things, or taking care of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a house involves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Architect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General Contractor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electrician&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plumber&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roofer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performing a surgical procedure involves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Family Doctor (or specialist) for pre-surgery physical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anesthesiologist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nurses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surgeon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surgical Assistants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Therapist for post surgery recovery (vocal therapist, physical therapist, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone in either two examples were to mess up, half-ass or just not show up, we’d end up in terrible positions, losing a lot of money, and potentially in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-while-designers-are-encouraged-sometimes-expected-to-involve-everybody-in-the-design-process-they-often-arent-afforded-the-same-luxury&quot;&gt;“So while designers are encouraged (sometimes expected) to involve everybody in the design process, they often aren’t afforded the same luxury.”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both design and development teams should be held accountable to involve team members in the project. If this doesn’t happen, it should be called out and corrected. However, it can be difficult to include everyone in the development process. It can be a barrier to show non-dev folks a technical issues or resolution if it isn’t visual, which can result in less interest in a topic (EX: talking about splicing array indicies to a sales person).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to bring all parties into the development process is to create the lowest barrier to review the design in the intended environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://patternlab.io/&quot;&gt;Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt; help bridge the gap between a design file and the finished product. They allow non-technical team members to interact with the design quickly and discuss unresolved ideas or “scratchpad” prototypes. It gets everyone on the same page earlier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-do-know-enough-to-tell-when-the-developers-are-fudging-things-and-its-always-fun-to-come-back-to-them-with-a-working-prototype-of-something-they-said-was-impossible-or-take-months-to-implement--but-i-digress&quot;&gt;“…I do know enough to tell when the developers are fudging things and it’s always fun to come back to them with a working prototype of something they said was impossible or take months to implement — but I digress.”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototypes come in many forms. Some prototypes are visual and meant as referential while others are coded. Both are great, they help resolve issues when something changes, moves and modifies when engaged. Few things to consider when providing prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A visual prototype is nice to &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; how it should work but can take a really long time to recreate identically. And often times falls short. A visual prototype should be delivered with &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/communicating-animation&quot;&gt;additional documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A coded prototype is a great way to meet a developer halfway. This allows an even lower barrier to ensure the prototype gets implemented as intended. Ensure the code meets the team’s code standards and if it doesn’t work with a developer to bring them up it up to par. In this case, it’s both parties job to make sure it’s production ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, it’s best to set up expectations on deliverables to-and-from both parties in the beginning. This way, when a prototype is handed over, both parties know what to expect and how it should be integrated in the the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;design-team-owns-the-design-experience-development-team-owns-the-development&quot;&gt;“Design team owns the design (experience), development team owns the development.”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If design owns the design, and development owns the code, who owns the finished product? This question comes to mind often when sitting with a designer combing over a site to polish off odds and ends. The two have differing opinions on how something should look or feel and then it gets awkward. The tone turns from “we are building this” to “I designed it, therefore it’s my decision”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ownership mentality becomes the enemy of collaboration when trying to work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The discipline owns the medium, the team owns the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a few (suggested) ideas to work by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and development own the design files. Both move through them, expect them to be clear, clean and navigable. If a design change comes up, the designer makes the appropriate changes to the design files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and development both own the coded results. Both own the displayed results of the code written. If the results are wrong or change, the developer updates the code to resolve the issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and development both own the language. Often times common terms come to surface and help discuss aspects of the work. If design and development communicate the same ideas differently it creates challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teams own the outcome, individual’s own tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no perfect, absolutely, indisputable answers to any of these topics or questions at hand. And some teams may find some techniques work better than others. The primary idea to ensure a better working experience is setting the table for communication and expectations from everyone. The sooner we know the less surprises come up. The more consistently we communicate the more effectively we help resolve issues and more forward. The better we work together as a team, the better we get as individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/reidhitt&quot;&gt;Reid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ptrikutam?lang=en&quot;&gt;Pavan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CMYKaytoe&quot;&gt;Kate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jackmakesthings&quot;&gt;Jack&lt;/a&gt; for their review, feedback and editing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/working-together.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/working-together.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Year In Review - 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot happened for me this year so I thought it might be helpful to reflect and review some of those things and try to think of things to improve on in 2016 in professional and personal aspects of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-job&quot;&gt;New Job.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2014 I worked as a web developer at a fashion trade show production company. I originally took the opportunity envisioning a freedom and responsibility that came with being a sole-developer at a company of about 30 employees. My intentions were to maintain the existing system, find opportunities to make it better and then implement solutions to improve things. Rinse, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about eight months that idea became harder and harder to maintain as more and more political decisions prevented me from performing the best job possible. At that point I decided to make a change. I didn’t want to leave for any other company, I wanted to make a calculated decision to move onto a company where I could learn and grow, be surrounded by a team and have an opportunity to learn from senior members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June of 2015 I took a position with Expand The Room (ETR), a small design/development shop in New York. December 1, 2015 was my six-month review and looking back, I’ve learned more in the last six months at ETR than I ever did at my previous employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mood has changed for the better. I enjoy my co-workers and the products we build every day. And while we all have our gripes, I genuinely like waking up and going to work everyday – which is something I’ve seeked for a long time. Somehow, Expand The Room has managed to hire responsible, smart and fun folks while providing them the space to do their job with resources to grow at the same time. I’ve never been happier in my professional (albeit short) career. PS - We’re hiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the knowledge has come from the team I work with and our open environment. We’ve created a space to take the time to learn about development, ownership and quality. Prior to this company, I never really understood what “professional quality” code was, but as I work with my colleagues, I learn a bit more about it each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, my boss, Ryan, has done a great job educating on things I never would’ve thought to learn on my own. Small things like declarative vs imperative approaches to development. Or the reason why sometimes the simpler option isn’t the best option. These things (and many others) took him years to learn and it’s something he loves to help early programmers learn as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freelance-work&quot;&gt;Freelance Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major change is the amount of freelance work I’ve done in 2015. A challenge imposed on myself this year was to really test the limits. I wanted to see how much I could do and find out where my threshold was for new knowledge, work, deadlines and clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;freelance-results&quot;&gt;2015 Freelance Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Freelance revenue: 48,435.00&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highest Paying Freelance Project: 14k&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longest Freelance Client: 1+ year (on going contract)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freelance Hours Worked:  506.61 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight Gained: 20+ lbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part was balancing work and personal life. I quickly found out freelancing on the side takes about twice as long as would freelancing full-time. It doesn’t mean I’m slower but rather I physically don’t have the hours to allocate to a project. Where someone might get 8-hours, I get 4-hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year I’ve tried various ways to manage my workload;  assigning days of the week for a particular client, assigning chunks of the week to particular clients, working in sprint cycles. After trying different approaches to solve the “time” problem it became very clear the best solution was to be honest, set expectations and say no when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication became a big area of improvement as well. Given the workload I’d taken on this year, I tried to be as open with clients as possible. I did it as an act of professionalism and honesty but also realized it became a great way to hold myself accountable. When I stopped keeping deadlines and schedules internally I started holding myself more accountable. It ended up making projects move faster and finding a solution for tough challenges easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fighting-burnout&quot;&gt;Fighting Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this year I’ve tried to be very cognizant of burnout. I enjoy what I do but still had moments of frustration and small bouts of burnout in 2015. My ability to separate work from play this year sucked, as most things took a backseat to freelancing (due to the my self-imposed challenge). But in the small moments of free time I was able to really cherish the time and make it count. I think the balance of full-time projects with freelance projects creates enough variation in my workload that it’s helped prevent burnout to some degree. Instead of hating the work I just get small instances of being tired. Overall, 2015, provided a lot of work, not as much down time to focus on other things but I plan on changing that in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-life&quot;&gt;Personal Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never thought my personal life would change as much as it did over the last twelve months. My professional life was my top priority and I certainly paid my dues. Three big things happened this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gained a lot of weight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had vocal surgery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved in with my girlfriend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight-gain&quot;&gt;Weight Gain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly correlated to the amount of work I took on in 2015. Hoping to create a much better schedule to make the time necessary to hit the gym on a weekly basis. I’m currently seeing a nutritionist to help shape up my eating habits and eating-choices as well. I’ve found that playing sports is my ideal way of staying active. While I enjoy the gym I tend to carry a lot of negativity around “working out” so I want to get back into basketball leagues or visit the YMCA at least once a week in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vocal-surgery&quot;&gt;Vocal Surgery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realized I’m not a young-buck anymore. In September of 2014 I lost my voice and never really recovered. Nine months later I visited a specialist to discover I had a polyp on my left vocal cord. Summer became the season of recovery as well as a 3-week period of vocal reset (absolutely no talking - post coming soon) post-surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vocal rest was especially fun when trying to do a code review with colleagues. And for what it’s worth, Apple’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;say&lt;/code&gt; command is pretty good, but still light-years away from human communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-overall&quot;&gt;Health Overall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably my worst year health-wise in my entire adult life. Looking to increase physical activity to at least once a week to start in 2016 to start and make it a real priority. This is the first time I’ve ever really disliked myself or my body and it’s really taking a toll on me mentally. I’d like to be proud of myself again (good ol’ high school days!) so this is definitely going to be very important in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relationships&quot;&gt;Relationships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things took a back seat this year, including relationships. Not super proud of it so I’m looking to recoup some of that in 2016. Thanks to digital communication I didn’t lose too much communication with friends but really wish I spent more face-time with friends and loved ones. Maybe it means leaving weekends open for socializing or a night or two a week to hang with folks. Not sure entirely what the solution is but it will be something I hope to explore and find a better fit into my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moved-in-with-my-girlfriend&quot;&gt;Moved in with My Girlfriend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biggest and most exciting part of this year by far. Love her to death and really happy we’re living together. But it clearly comes with its own growing pains. We’re getting better at cohabiting the same space in a way that allows us to do our own thing while still being respective and inclusive to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally got settled in November so looking forward to turning this place into a home even more than it already is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was worried about my freelance workload in 2015 and how it’d affect our relationship but she was always super supportive. In 2016 we’ll be discussing freelance work (and all my work) more openly to make sure its not getting the best of our relationship (or me). This is also something I plan on writing more about in the future. I’m quickly realizing my freelance work not only affects my life but those around me and definitely want to document how it grows and changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal-projects&quot;&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most personal projects fell by the wayside due to freelance work but I’d like to make time for them in 2016. At first I wondered why I was unable to stick to some of those side projects (even one’s I invested money into) but I quickly realized two things: they were not generating revenue immediately like freelancing and they were not a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a goal to create 12 things in 2015 but failed horribly. While freelancing work could be considered apart of this goal, I was still nowhere near the 12 things I set out to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on baking more (some friends know about this) and putting on a few more Beta Tasting events throughout the year, too. The truth, though, is baking 100 cookies for friends/people is really time consuming and costly so I’m thinking about doing them in smaller batches or increase ticket quantity to make up for the cost of ingredients and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote - If you want to stay in the loop about cookies, I’ve got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pbj.im/spiltmilksignup&quot;&gt;mailing list you can subscribe as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-spent&quot;&gt;Time Spent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I tracked a lot of time, working or otherwise, and it’s been really helpful to determine if I spent time doing things I deem “of value”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read about five books in 2015; a mix of fiction and nonfiction. Hoping to read more in general and try to alternate between fiction and nonfiction in 2016. I’ve discovered I enjoy technical books but they get dry quickly and nonfiction really gets me excited to keep reading (and helps creativity) so hopefully it will create a balance to read more. If you have any book recommendation send them over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tv-watched&quot;&gt;TV Watched:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched over 160 hours of TV in 2015 (that I’ve tracked) and it definitely wasn’t worth it. This doesn’t any live sports. I could spend this time doing other stuff like going to the gym, working on something fun, hanging out with my girlfriend or learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;movies-watched&quot;&gt;Movies Watched&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same as the TV section above, I spent roughly 54+ hours in 2015 watching movies. The good news: that’s significantly less than the past two years (I write down every movie I watch) but looking forward to spending my time doing things of higher quality in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;2015 Overall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was definitely a different year for me. I was thrown a bunch of curveballs and for the most part, I performed accordingly (good or bad, I’m not sure). After the freelance “challenge” this year I’m hoping to make 2016 a more impactful year for my personal life. Shifting focus from work and onto my health, relationships and personal time. All the while still freelancing, just not as crazily as 2015. I think the crux of this is to focus on structure, priority and importance. Some aspects of this will be personally decided on while others a joint effort for my girlfriend and I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I think 2015 was a pretty solid, fun and interesting year and I expect no less from 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/year-in-review-2015.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/year-in-review-2015.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hardest Part</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Programming is a tough line of work. Not because its hard to learn or to implement, but because you constantly face failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenario feels identical each time, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have an idea on how to build something or fix an issue. You get behind your computer and start working. The first solution didn’t work, neither did the second, nor did the third. Twenty minutes turns into an hour which turns into four and at this point you’ve met enough small failures you feel like a big failure yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You feel frustrated, worried, scared, paralyzed, annoyed and just generally not defeated. You feel like you’re in quicksand and each move you make while in this funk only digs you deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point you ask for help. The person you ask gets it done pretty quickly and now you’ve got two new failures weighing you down: you had to ask for help and now you’re comparing you’re failure to someone else’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people say to turn these moments into a learning experience, and I whole-heartedly agree. But sometimes we also have to realize we’re scared, upset or frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hardest part isn’t programming. The hardest part is perseverance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perseverance to continue no matter how much you know, how fast you’re going or how difficult the task may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/the-hardest-part.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/the-hardest-part.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 The Goals List</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An idea came to me at the end of 2014 - in 2015 I would create one thing each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating something is fun, but is often hard and takes a long time. Due to this very nature, we often build less than we’d like and never really create a habit of producing our own &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to try and release a new project each month and write about it here in hopes of creating a habit of releasing my own creations out into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining a “project” was difficult at first. Should it be personal projects? Should it be client projects? I realized limiting what I make to personal or client categories detracts from the goal of simply &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;making something&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. So the goal of producing something each month in 2015 is a mixture of personal projects and client projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Goals List is on the home page in a listed format. You can also read a little more in-depth on each page, or &lt;a href=&quot;/goals&quot;&gt;check out the goals page as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/goals&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-project&quot;&gt;View Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/goals.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finally A &quot;New&quot; Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me forever but I finally built a “new” site. When I say “new” I just mean something that wasn’t a landing page with basically nothing on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bit more built out, granted nothing that’s worth a huge award or “ohh-ing” and “aww-ing”. Just something that is better than what I had before and is an actual system that allows editing/updating to happen a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this site, I decided to build on a static CMS I haven’t tried before - Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m familar with liquid templating but haven’t really used it too much and figured this would be a great opportunity to get into something new for a quick weekend project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping this new site and CMS will enable me to write more and document my work frequently. I’m totally aware this won’t &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; me write, but considering it’s pretty easy, maybe I’ll be more open to the idea of documenting the stuff I do in my life, personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pbj.me/writing/new-site.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pbj.me/writing/new-site.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
